VERA ARRINGTON, MSN, APRN, AGACNP-BC

836 Regal Bluff Lane • Desoto, Texas • 75115 veraarrington3868@gmail.com • 972-603-5718

Professional Summary

Dedicated and patient focused Adult-Gerontology Acute Care Nurse Practitioner with proven strengths in acute patient care. Displays an exceptional aptitude to deliver positive patient outcomes in a fast-paced environment while simultaneously building productive relationships. Known for exceptional interpersonal and communication skills, the ability to manage competing priorities, as well as maintaining accurate and efficient documentation.

Skills

- Advanced assessment skills and strong clinical judgment as a Nurse Practitioner
- Wound care management
- Incision & drainage of simple abscesses
- Suturing & skin adhesive
- Splinting extremities
- EKG interpretation
- Venipuncture expert
- Adept at prioritizing/managing deadlines
- Computer proficiencies in MS Word, MS Excel, Outlook, and EMR

Education

Master of Science in Nursing, 05/2018

Walden University

Minneapolis, Minnesota

• Adult Gerontology Acute Care Nurse Practitioner Specialty

Bachelor of Science in Nursing, 12/2013

University of Texas at Arlington Arlington, Texas

Associate of Applied Science, 05/2011

El Centro College Dallas Texas

Clinical Practicum Experience

Hospitalist

• Develop treatment plans for acute and chronic diseases

- Perform necessary diagnostic tests and procedures
- Emphasize preventative care and disease management
- Conduct comprehensive physical exams for adult and aging patients associated with comorbidities
- Prescribe medications and treatments
- Evaluate patient outcomes to prevent future re-admissions

Internal Medicine

- o Provide compassionate primary care services including comprehensive and focused physical examinations, health assessments, diagnoses, and treatment of acute and chronic illnesses for the adult population
- o Manage chronic conditions such as diabetes, hypertension, arthritis, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, and thyroid disorders
- Assess need for appropriate lab tests, order and interpret results under the supervision of preceptor
- Collaborate with medical specialties through appropriate referrals

Emergency Medicine

- Deliver primary care in the emergency department: Triage and treat urgent and nonemergency medical conditions in collaboration with the emergency room attending physician.
- Order and interpret diagnostic tests and labs
- o Collaborate with surgical and medical specialties to ensure optimal patient outcomes

Gerontology

- o Manage overall patient care, including acute and chronic ailments, as well as changes in lifestyle and development issues
- Develop treatment plans for acute and chronic diseases
- o Educate patients on health promotion throughout the aging process
- o Perform diagnostic tests and screening evaluations
- o Emphasize preventative care and disease management
- Conduct comprehensive physical exams for aging patients and problems associated with co-morbidities
- o Prescribe and manage medications

Professional Experience

Registered Nurse

Department of Veteran Affairs, 04/2012 to Present

Dallas, Texas

Positions held:

Utilization Management RN, 11/2016 to Present

- Complete admission screening reviews to determine if the patient meets medical necessity
- Perform McKesson InterQual Utilization reviews on admission and continued stays of inpatients

- Make recommendations for transfer of patient to the appropriate level of care
- Collaborate with interdisciplinary team rounds to ensure all patients are meeting inpatient
 criteria and choose the best disposition based on needs for those patients who are ready
 for discharge to home, subacute, or long-term care
- Perform gain and loss report to identify admissions and discharges
- Referral to the Physician Utilization Management Advisor as necessary

Case Management, RN, 11/2014 to 11/2016

- Assess and interview patient concerning home care needs, perform McKesson InterQual Utilization reviews for continued patient stays
- Precept and serve as mentor to new case managers
- Coordinate resources and services for inpatient and outpatients
- Participate in interdisciplinary team meeting to anticipate and ensure discharge needs are met

Emergency Department Registered Nurse, 4/2012 to 11/2014

- Provide evidence-based care to patients and families with sensitivity and respect to their expectations, age, cultural, and individual needs
- Recognize clinical changes in patient status and implements appropriate interventions with concise communication of assessment and plan of care to physician
- Assess need for labs and diagnostics, obtain order and report results to physician
- Perform treatments and assist physician with bedside procedures
- Educate patients/families about medications, disease condition and health maintenance

Affiliations

- American Nurses Credentialing Center, ANCC
- American Nurses Association, ANA
- American Association of Nurse Practitioners, AANP

Certifications

- American Nursing Credentialing Center, AGACNP-BC, issued 10/2018, current
- American Heart Association, BLS, current
- American Heart Association, ACLS, current

Licensure

- Advanced Practice Registered Nurse, State of Texas, issued 11/2018, current
- Registered Nurse, State of Texas, issued 12/2011, current

Interests

- Quality improvement Projects
- Going to church, shopping, and fishing